Yasir Sabab

Contact: 01626401683 E-mail: <u>sabab007@gmail.com</u>

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/yasirsabab/

Experience: 8.7years

Industry Expertise: FMCG / Health Tech/ Building Materials / Textile / Educational Institutes

Portfolio's Cumulative Revenue: 10+ Billion BDT



CAREER SUMMARY

Results-driven Brand & Marketing Professional with more than 8 years of experience in Marketing, Branding, Business Development, Market Research, Digital Marketing, PR & Communication and Sales. Effective communicator with excellent relationship & team management skills. Knowledgeable about FMCG trends, market conditions, and customer buying habits. Augmented my experience with initiatives such as brand creation, lead generation, channel partner cultivation, customer segmentation/profiling, data mining, analyzing, and measuring ROMI & ROI.

SUMMERY OF PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

ASSISTANT MARKETING MANAGER & BRAND LEAD – GRAMEEN DIGITAL HEALTH (FORMER TELENOR HEALTH), (DECEMBER 2021 – CONTINUING) CONCERN OF GRAMEEN TELECOM TRUST

- Develop marketing & brand annual plan and budget for "Grameen Digital Health" to establish the digital healthcare category (online medicine, telemedicine, online home diagnostic etc.) for brand awareness and ensure to achieve the sales goals
- Ensure maximum brand presence and engagement among target group to increase brand equity as per brand guidelines through different levels of communication channel ATL, BTL, Digital, PR, Merchandising, Outdoor, and Events
- Develop creatives ideas (static, dynamics, push notifications, GIF) for different digital media channels (social medias, GDN, others' E-commerce platforms, Websites) and App
- Leading different qualitative and quantitative research activities to check brand health, identify trends, insights about the market to develop different tactical and long-term marketing strategies for the implementation
- Supervising and maintaining relationships with retainer agencies (Creative, Digital, PR, Research) to
 uphold the corporate and brand image as well as for the development of long-term brand strategy,
 brand communication, and implementation
- Measure all marketing activities and campaigns in contrast with business KPIs and ROI of the marketing budget BDT 120 million
- Managing team towards achieving business goal

ASSISTANT MANAGER – BRAND & MARKETING, ORGANIKARE (A CONCERN OF GEMCON GROUP), (APRIL 2021 – DECEMBER 2021)

- Develop marketing plan, budget and implementing strategies that resonate with the target market
- Planning and executing marketing initiatives including campaigns, events, sponsorships, and others
- Building brand awareness and increasing brand value and profitability
- Increasing product sales and market share through marketing strategies
- Measuring and reporting on campaign performance and assessing KPIs and ROI
- Overseeing the production of advertisements, promotional materials, and campaigns
- Ensuring that messaging and marketing activities are aligned with brand and company values
- Develop plan and strategies for all digital marketing channels

CORPORATE BRAND REPRESENTATIVE – BRAND & COMMUNICATION, UPAY (A CONCERN OF UCB BANK), (MAY 2021 – JUNE 2022) – FREELANCE

- Represent brand in a mass market through different channels (Billboard, ATM Booth, TV, Digital Media)
- Creating awareness for a company's services and products

SENIOR BRAND EXECUTIVE – BRAND & COMMUNICATION, ORGANIKARE (A CONCERN OF GEMCON GROUP, (APRIL 2019 – MARCH 2021)

- Prepare effective brand plans and brand budget according to the marketing strategies
- Plan and implement ATL & BTL activities such as promotional activities, print advertisements, events, point-of-sales marketing etc
- Create, direct and monitor product launch thematic advertising, advertorial, editorial approval and joint promotion with media partners and third parties
- Co-work with respective trade channels for promotional mechanism, special offers, instore display and POSM materials
- Ensure brand presence in Modern Trade, Corporate and Retail market for business growth
- Identify new product category expansion to develop sales and ensure quality packaging
- Liaising and managing with different agencies, channels, and newspapers to smooth brand communication

EXECUTIVE – BRAND & PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT, RAK CERAMICS BANGLADESH LIMITED, (JULY 2015 – APRIL 2019)

- Communicate and coordinate with selected media houses (Print & Electronic) for implementing the marketing campaign as per plan
- Responsible for brand building, liaising with agencies, production of in-house promotional materials and publications, preparing press releases, organizing promotional activities
- Carrying out local brand building and below the line marketing activities. Implementing promotional activities
- Coordinating in marketing & branding campaigns including dealer management
- Entail marketing and advertising activities to ensure consistency with product line strategy
- Providing market analysis information pertaining to competitors, trends, and activities

TEACHER ASSISTANT (UNDER THE FACULTY KHOZAIMA F. ZIAUDDIN, SCHOOL OF BUSINESS), ULAB (JANUARY 2015 - MAY 2015)

- Prepare lesson outlines and plans in assigned subject areas, and submit outlines to teachers for review
- Observe students' performance, and record relevant data to assess progress

MANAGEMENT TRAINEE OFFICER - PROCUREMENT, GRAPHICS TEXTILES LTD, (AUGUST 2014 – DECEMBER 2014)

- Prepared and processed requisitions and purchased orders for supplies and equipment
- Reviewed inventories and orders as required
- Interacted with suppliers on a day-to-day basis and maintain report
- Prepared reports regarding market conditions and merchandise costs

SPECIALIZED KNOWLEDGE

- Brand plan & strategy development
- Exploring new branding opportunities, event and activation plan & execution
- Marketing communication development and implementation

ACHEIVEMENTS

- Achievement Award for Promotion and Best Performance in 2020
- RAK Ceramics "Best Brand Award" 2017 in Ceramic Tiles Category by Bangladesh Brand Forum in association with Kanter Milward
- RAK Ceramics "Best Brand Award" 2018 in Ceramic Tiles Category by Bangladesh Brand Forum in association with Nelson

TRAININGS & PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATION

- Fundamentals of Digital Marketing, Google
- Training on Leading Change, Gemcon Group
- Training on Price and Margin, ULAB, Gemcon Group
- Training on SAP, Robert Bosch GmbH, India RAK Ceramics UAE & RAK Ceramics (BD)
- Training on Redefining Retail in Bangladesh, Bangladesh Brand Forum
- Advanced Managerial Communication, Self-Leadership 21st Century Managerial Mindset by SAPIEN
- Training on Microsoft Excel, RAK Ceramics Bangladesh Limited
- Training on the Challenge of Ceramic Branding & Export, BCMEA
- Digital Marketing Summit, Bangladesh Brand Forum
- Career Services & Resume Writing, Business Club of United International University
- Training on branding yourself & your firm, United International University & JCI

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

- Master of Business Administration (MBA)
 University of Liberal Arts Bangladesh
 (ULAB), Major in Marketing (2018)
- Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC)
 Birshreshtha Munshi Abdur Rouf Rifles
 College (2008), Group: Business Studies
- Bachelor of Business Administration (BBA)
 United International University (UIU),
 Major in HRM (2014)
- Secondary School Certificate (SSC)
 Lalmatia Housing Society Boys High School (2006), Group: Science

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Date of Birth: 5th November 1991 **Marital Status:** Married

REFERENCES:

Mr. Monirul Hassan

Commercial Director
Grameen Digital Health
Mobile Number: (+880) 1844053

Mobile Number: (+880) 1844053851

Mr. Mohammed Khaled Hasan

General Manager - Marketing Sheltech Ceramics Ltd.

Mobile Number: (+88) 0171627264

Yasir Sabab